Faculty of Education fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Committee files, 1965 - 2000; F-233-3; 4.7 m of textual records 1 sound recording; Physical description: includes 4 audio cassettes (located in sub-series 3).
  - Professional Programs Committee files, 1969 - 1986, predominant 1976 - 1986; F-233-3-7; 10 cm of textual records; Faculty of Education. Professional Programs Committee
    - Papers and correspondence, 1977 - 1980; F-233-3-7-0-5 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-8-7-0-358.
    - Agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1980; F-233-3-7-0-6 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-2-0-4.
    - Papers and correspondence, 1980 - 1981; F-233-3-7-0-7 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-8-7-0-435.
    - Agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1981; F-233-3-7-0-8 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-2-0-5.
    - Agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1982; F-233-3-7-0-9 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-2-0-6.
    - Agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1983; F-233-3-7-0-10 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-2-0-7.
    - Agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1984; F-233-3-7-0-11 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-2-0-8.
    - Agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1985; F-233-3-7-0-12 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-2-0-9.
    - Agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1985 - 1986; F-233-3-7-0-13 (Archival box - standard 233-33)
  - Graduate Programs Committee files, 1969 - 1994; F-233-3-8; 54 cm of textual records; Faculty of Education. Graduate Programs Committee
    Mention of a Standing Committee on Graduate Studies appears in the minutes of the Faculty of Education's Faculty Meeting in December 1965, but its level of activity and continuity with later committees is not clear. At the faculty's April 1969 meeting, it approved the establishment of the Graduate Studies Committee. With the faculty's 1972 reorganization, it was renamed the Graduate Programs Committee, and it continues as an active body as of this writing (July 2008). Its mandate is to fulfill the responsibilities of departmental and faculty graduate studies committees as established by university policy and to review and make recommendations to the faculty on all matters relating to the graduate programs and course of the faculty.
    Rules for composition of the committee have varied over time. From 1969 to 1972 memberships comprise the Dean, a representative from the Graduate Studies Committee of each department of the faculty, and a graduate student from each department. After 1972, the committee has been composed of the Director of Graduate Programs (Chair), the Dean (non-voting), and elected faculty members (four in total), faculty associates (one), and graduate students (one plus alternate).
    Sub-series consists of records made or received by the Graduate Programs Committee in the course of its activities and deliberations. Activities documented include review of course and program proposals, development of policies and procedures, curriculum development, support for graduate students, and liaison with the Senate Committee on Graduate Studies and with the Office of Graduate Studies. Records include course and program proposals and recommendations, draft calendar statements, correspondence, reports, and motions.
    Note that the there are gaps in the holdings. There are no committee records from 1981 to 1984 or for 1989.
    Material dated 1980 and earlier was previously arranged by the Archives into separate files for agendas and minutes on the one hand, and supporting papers on the other. Material dated 1985 and later were transferred to the Archives in binders, sub-divided by month, and have been preserved in their original order. For each monthly meeting, the records consist of an agenda, the minutes of the previous meeting (for approval), and the supporting papers for the current meeting.
    Other material relating to the Faculty of Education's graduate programs can be found throughout this fonds, but see especially sub-series F-233-7-4, "Graduate Programs publications."
    - GPC supporting papers, 1969; F-233-3-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-2.
    - GPC correspondence, 1969; F-233-3-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-3.
    - GPC correspondence, 1970; F-233-3-8-0-3 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-7.
    - GPC supporting papers, 1970; F-233-3-8-0-4 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-5.
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1970 - 1971; F-233-3-8-0-5 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-4.
    - GPC correspondence, 1971; F-233-3-8-0-6 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-8.
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1971 - 1972; F-233-3-8-0-7 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-9.
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1973; F-233-3-8-0-8 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-10.
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1974 - 1975; F-233-3-8-0-9 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1976; F-233-3-8-0-10 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-13.
    - GPC supporting papers, 1976; F-233-3-8-0-11 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-14.
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1977; F-233-3-8-0-12 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-15.
    - GPC supporting papers, 1977; F-233-3-8-0-13 (Archival box - standard 233-39)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-16.
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1978; F-233-3-8-0-14 (Archival box - standard 233-40)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-17.
    - GPC supporting papers, 1978; F-233-3-8-0-15 (Archival box - standard 233-40)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-18.
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1979; F-233-3-8-0-16 (Archival box - standard 233-40)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-19.
    - GPC supporting papers, 1979; F-233-3-8-0-17 (Archival box - standard 233-40)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-20.
    - GPC agenda and minutes, 1980; F-233-3-8-0-18 (Archival box - standard 233-40)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-21.
    - GPC supporting papers, 1980; F-233-3-8-0-19 (Archival box - standard 233-40)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-22.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1985; F-233-3-8-0-20 (Archival box - standard 233-40)
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1986; F-233-3-8-0-21 (Archival box - standard 233-40)
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1987; F-233-3-8-0-22 (Archival box - standard 233-41)
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1987; F-233-3-8-0-23 (Archival box - standard 233-41)
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1988; F-233-3-8-0-24 (Archival box - standard 233-41)
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1990; F-233-3-8-0-25 (Archival box - standard 233-41)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-26.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1991; F-233-3-8-0-26 (Archival box - standard 233-41)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-27.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1991; F-233-3-8-0-27 (Archival box - standard 233-41)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-28.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 3, 1991; F-233-3-8-0-28 (Archival box - standard 233-42)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-29.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1992; F-233-3-8-0-29 (Archival box - standard 233-42)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-30.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1992; F-233-3-8-0-30 (Archival box - standard 233-42)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-31.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 3, 1992; F-233-3-8-0-31 (Archival box - standard 233-42)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-32.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1993; F-233-3-8-0-32 (Archival box - standard 233-42)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-33.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1993; F-233-3-8-0-33 (Archival box - standard 233-42)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-34.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 3, 1993; F-233-3-8-0-34 (Archival box - standard 233-42)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-35.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1994; F-233-3-8-0-35 (Archival box - small 233-43)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-36.
    - GPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1994; F-233-3-8-0-36 (Archival box - small 233-43)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-7-0-0-37.
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Reorganization files, 1971; F-233-3-9; 1 cm of textual records; Faculty of Education. Ad Hoc Committee on Reorganization
    The administrative history of the Faculty of Education's Ad Hoc Committee on Reorganization is not well-established. A "Re-organization Committee" appears in 1968 (see minutes of the Faculty Meeting, 30 September 1968). The Ad Hoc Committee, on the other hand, appears to have been active mainly in 1971, with a mandate to canvass and investigate proposals for re-structuring the faculty. Re-organization was finalized in 1972 with the abolition of the faculty's departmental structure based on centres and its replacement by a unitary faculty with functional program-area division.
    Sub-series consists of one file containing records relating to the activities of the committee. Records include correspondence, reports, proposals, and recommendations.
    Material relating to the 1972 re-organization of the faculty can be found throughout the fonds, but see especially sub-series F-233-1-2, "Dean of Education subject files."
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Reorganization, 1971; F-233-3-9-0-1 (Archival box - standard 233-32)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-3-5-0-1.
  - Undergraduate Programs Committee files, 1972 - 1999, predominant 1983 - 1999; F-233-3-10; 78 cm of textual records; Faculty of Education. Undergraduate Programs Committee
    The establishment of the Undergraduate Studies Committee was approved by the Faculty of Education at its Faculty Meeting of November 1968. Although the records of the committee do not begin until 1972, reference to its activities can be found in the Faculty Meeting minutes before this date. With the re-organization of the faculty in 1972 it became known as the Undergraduate Programs Committee and under this name continues as an active committee as of this writing (July 2008). Its mandate is to consider and make recommendations to the faculty on all matters relating to the undergraduate courses and programs of the faculty; to recommend candidates for the Bachelor of Education degree; and to fulfill the responsibilities of departmental and faculty undergraduate studies committees.
    The committee's composition has varied over time. Originally membership comprised the Dean plus one faculty member and one student from each of the faculty's various departments. With the restructuring of the faculty in 1972, composition was changed to consist of the Director of Undergraduate Programs, Dean (non-voting), four members elected by and from the faculty, and two student representatives (originally named by the Director on nomination by the Education Student Union, later elected directly by it).
    Sub-series consists of records made or received by the Undergraduate Programs Committee in the course of its activities and deliberations. Activities documented include review of degree requirements and curriculum content, calendar revisions, development of policies and procedures, staffing priorities, and liaison with the Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies. Records include meeting agendas and minutes, reports, correspondence, program proposals and recommendations, course descriptions, new course proposal forms, and statistics. Note that there are gaps in the holdings, with few records before 1983 (just two files from 1972 and 1974 respectively).
    Other material relating to the Faculty of Education's undergraduate programs can be found throughout this fonds, but see especially sub-series F-233-7-5, "Undergraduate Programs publications."
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1972; F-233-3-10-0-1 (Archival box - standard 233-35)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-1.
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1974; F-233-3-10-0-2 (Archival box - standard 233-35)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-2.
    - UPC agenda and minutes, 1983; F-233-3-10-0-3 (Archival box - standard 233-35)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-3.
    - UPC supporting papers, 1983; F-233-3-10-0-4 (Archival box - standard 233-35)
    - UPC agenda and minutes, 1984; F-233-3-10-0-5 (Archival box - standard 233-35)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-6.
    - UPC papers, 1984; F-233-3-10-0-6 (Archival box - standard 233-35)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1985; F-233-3-10-0-7 (Archival box - standard 233-36)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1985; F-233-3-10-0-8 (Archival box - standard 233-36)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 3, 1985; F-233-3-10-0-9 (Archival box - standard 233-36)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1986; F-233-3-10-0-10 (Archival box - standard 233-36)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1986; F-233-3-10-0-11 (Archival box - standard 233-36)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 3, 1986; F-233-3-10-0-12 (Archival box - standard 233-36)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 4, 1986; F-233-3-10-0-13 (Archival box - standard 233-36)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1987; F-233-3-10-0-14 (Archival box - standard 233-36)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1987; F-233-3-10-0-15 (Archival box - standard 233-37)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 3, 1987; F-233-3-10-0-16 (Archival box - standard 233-37)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 4, 1987; F-233-3-10-0-17 (Archival box - standard 233-37)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 5, 1987; F-233-3-10-0-18 (Archival box - standard 233-37)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1988; F-233-3-10-0-19 (Archival box - standard 233-37)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1988; F-233-3-10-0-20 (Archival box - standard 233-37)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 3, 1988; F-233-3-10-0-21 (Archival box - standard 233-38)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1989; F-233-3-10-0-22 (Archival box - standard 233-38)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 2, 1989; F-233-3-10-0-23 (Archival box - standard 233-38)
    - UPC agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1990; F-233-3-10-0-24 (Archival box - standard 233-38)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-30.
    - UPC agenda and minutes, 1991; F-233-3-10-0-25 (Archival box - standard 233-38)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-32.
    - UPC supporting papers, vol. 1, 1991; F-233-3-10-0-26 (Archival box - standard 233-38)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-33.
    - UPC supporting papers, vol. 2, 1991; F-233-3-10-0-27 (Archival box - standard 233-38)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-34.
    - UPC supporting papers, vol. 3, 1991; F-233-3-10-0-28 (Archival box - small 233-43)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-6-0-0-35.
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1991; F-233-3-10-0-29 (Archival box - standard 233-82)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1991; F-233-3-10-0-30 (Archival box - standard 233-82)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1992; F-233-3-10-0-31 (Archival box - standard 233-82)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1992; F-233-3-10-0-32 (Archival box - standard 233-82)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 3, 1992; F-233-3-10-0-33 (Archival box - standard 233-82)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1993; F-233-3-10-0-34 (Archival box - standard 233-82)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1993; F-233-3-10-0-35 (Archival box - standard 233-83)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1994; F-233-3-10-0-36 (Archival box - standard 233-83)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1994; F-233-3-10-0-37 (Archival box - standard 233-83)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 3, 1994; F-233-3-10-0-38 (Archival box - standard 233-83)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1995; F-233-3-10-0-39 (Archival box - standard 233-83)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1995; F-233-3-10-0-40 (Archival box - standard 233-83)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 1, 1996; F-233-3-10-0-41 (Archival box - standard 233-83)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, vol. 2, 1996; F-233-3-10-0-42 (Archival box - standard 233-83)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, 1997; F-233-3-10-0-43 (Archival box - standard 233-80)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, 1998; F-233-3-10-0-44 (Archival box - standard 233-80)
    - UPC agenda, minutes and supporting papers, 1999; F-233-3-10-0-45 (Archival box - standard 233-80)
  - Faculty Tenure Committee files, 1974, 1978; F-233-3-11; 2 cm of textual records; Faculty of Education. Faculty Tenure Committee
    The Faculty of Education's Faculty Tenure Committee was established in 1972 as the successor to the faculty's Salaries and Promotions Committee and continues as of this writing (July 2008) as an active committee of the faculty. Its mandate is to make recommendations on contract renewal, tenure, and promotion in accord with university policies and procedures; and to consult with the Chair with respect to the merit component of annual salary increase recommendations. Six members and the Chair are elected from the faculty, with the Chair normally a tenured faculty member of the rank of Full or Associate Professor.
    Sub-series consists of two files (from 1974 and 1978) containing records relating to the activities of the Faculty Tenure Committee. Records include correspondence, salary recommendations, meeting minutes, committee procedures, and reports.
    For other committee records in this fonds relating to tenure, salaries and promotions, see the archives of the predecessor committee, the Salaries and Promotions Commitee (sub-series F-233-3-6).
    - Dean's memoranda, 1974; F-233-3-11-0-1 (Archival box - standard 233-32)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-3-4-0-4.
    - Memoranda, 1978; F-233-3-11-0-2 (Archival box - standard 233-32)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-3-4-0-5.
  - Savage Beagles / Management Meeting files, 1974 - 1987; F-233-3-12; 17 cm of textual records; Faculty of Education. Savage Beagles Meeting
    The administrative history of the Savage Beagles Meeting is not well-established. It was not an official standing committee of the Faculty of Education, but appears to have begun some time after 1972 as a meeting called by the Director of Professional Programs and attended by faculty members involved in PDP. The records of the meeting begin in 1974. It was originally called the Director's Meeting, renamed Management Meeting in 1980, and the Dicord Meeting in 1986. In August 1986 the group went on retreat to Whistler BC, and henceforth the committee was known as the Savage Beagles after the name of a Whistler pub.
    Sub-series consists of records made or received by the Management Meeting / Savage Beagles in the course of their activities and deliberations. Activities documented include programs for school associates, faculty associates and program coordinators (conferences, events, orientation); external programs planning and liaison with school districts; PDP staffing and budget; and PDP curriculum, intake, and student placement. Records prior to 1985 consist solely of meeting agenda and minutes; from 1985-1987 meeting support papers were also maintained, including correspondence, reports, orientation schedules, and lists of appointments of associates and coordinators.
    - Director's meeting: agenda, minutes, 1974 - 1976; F-233-3-12-0-1 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-1.
    - Director's meeting: agenda, minutes, 1978; F-233-3-12-0-2 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-2.
    - Director's meeting: agenda, minutes, 1979; F-233-3-12-0-3 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-3.
    - Management meeting: agenda, minutes, 1980; F-233-3-12-0-4 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-4.
    - Management meeting: agenda, minutes, 1981; F-233-3-12-0-5 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-5.
    - Management meeting: agenda, minutes, 1982; F-233-3-12-0-6 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-6.
    - Management meeting: agenda, minutes, 1983; F-233-3-12-0-7 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-7.
    - Management meeting: agenda, minutes, 1984; F-233-3-12-0-8 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-8.
    - Management meeting: agenda, minutes, 1985; F-233-3-12-0-9 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-9.
    - Management meeting: agenda, minutes, supporting papers, 1985; F-233-3-12-0-10 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-10.
    - Management meeting: agenda, minutes, 1986; F-233-3-12-0-11 (Archival box - standard 233-34)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-22-5-3-0-16.
    - Dicord meeting: agenda, minutes, supporting papers, vol. 1, 1986; F-233-3-12-0-12 (Archival box - standard 233-35)